[ Woman Screams ]
[ Woman # 1 ] I am there .
[ Woman # 2 ] Is she in contact ? Shh .
[ Woman # 1 ] Yes , I am there .
[ Labored Breathing ]
I see - -
[ Object Clattering ]
There 's the contact .
She 's just entered ... into contact - -
She 's entered into contact - -
- Into contact - - - [ Woman # 1 Breathing Heavily ]
[ Screams ]
[ Spirits Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
The dead ! I see the dead !
The city of the dead ! [ Gasping ]
But - -
No ! Hold the link . Don 't break it .
Hold it . It 's critical for Mary . Don 't break the link . Don 't break it .
[ Screams ]
Mary ! Mary !
[ Gasping ]
[ Spirits Moaning , Muttering ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Muttering Continues ]
[ Spirits Moaning ] [ Rope Creaking On Branch ]
I 'm afraid Mary 's dead .
No ! [ Sobbing ]
No ! Mary !
Mary ! [ Sobbing ] Mary !
[ Siren Blaring ]
All right .
Maybe I 've got no imagination ,
but your story is a little tough to swallow .
James McLuhan .
Busted twice for peddling and possession .
That 's right . So ?
And you expect me to believe ...
that Mary Woodhouse died out of sheer fright ...
while you were having a séance ?
Mm-hmm .
Okay , fellas , you help us ,
we 'll help you .
What were you on ?
Coke ? Grass ?
[ Shouting ] Where 's the stash , down the toilet ? [ Woman ] You don 't deserve any help !
You 're a comic-book version , Sergeant .
Well , look better in your mug shot , you know ?
The Great Theresa , the master medium .
Yeah , for you , it 's all in the Book of , uh - -
Your Book of - - What 's it again ?
Enoch . Yeah . Enoch .
According to you ,
this poor girl is dead because of a book ...
that was written 4,000 years ago , correct ?
That 's right .
I would find such an unusual paradox of tremendous appeal terribly stimulating ...
if I were a sleuth . Hmm .
The explanation in every detail of a crime ...
before it 's been committed .
Lady , you 're either on grass or you 're pulling my leg .
[ Chuckles ] No . The problem is in your mind .
It can 't accept the truth .
But I 'll help you just the same .
- In the Book of Enoch , the killer is - - - Jesus ! Sergeant , come here and look !
[ Spirit Moaning ]
[ Moaning ]
Who 's playing games here ? Come out of the floor , out of nowhere .
Who lives downstairs ?
It 's vacant . Has been for 26 years .
But how the heck did - - Don 't you start acting up too .
It 's only a prank ,
and I 'll find out what 's behind it even if I have to tear the whole building apart .
Keep refusing the truth .
At this very precise moment ,
in some other distant town ,
horrendously awful things are happening - -
things that would shatter your imagination .
[ Bird Shrieking ]
[ Shrieking Continues ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Muttering ]
[ Door Creaks ]
[ Chuckling ]
[ Squishing ]
[ Whimpering ]
Hi , Officer . I 'm , uh , looking for Sergeant Clay .
And who are you ? Oh , I 'm Peter Bell .
You see , I 'm with the New York - - Don 't tell me .
You 're a newspaper reporter , right ?
I can smell you guys a mile away .
You 're right . I 'm a journalist .
Look , there 's this rumor down at the station house ...
that , uh , well , someone kind of died mysteriously ,
and I wanna talk to Sergeant Bell about it .
It 's not gonna be any mystery how the next guy dies ...
if I let any unauthorized people in that house .
Look , uh ,
isn 't there a way that , uh , maybe you and I could come to a gentlemen 's agreement ?
You 're talking into my deaf ear , pal .
Now , take my advice and beat it before the sergeant comes out .
[ Sighs ] Okay .
I 'll take your advice .
[ Wind Howling ]
It 's like we 're in the wrong season suddenly .
Damn dust . All these high winds .
Pretty unusual .
By the way , I hear Cindy Horan never went home last night .
So ? Ha . It sure wouldn 't be the first time .
I remember once she was sitting in - -
[ Shatters Loudly ]
You know something ?
Ever since Father Thomas hanged himself ,
Dunwich ain 't been the same .
It 's kind of scary .
Uh , a few beers , and you fellas start seeing ghouls and devils all over the place .
Well , you saw what happened , didn 't ya ?
Sure , but that doesn 't mean there isn 't any explanation .
Could 've been a truck passing by , a vibration .
Anyway , I 've lost my mirror .
You forget who our ancestors were .
[ Chuckles ] No . I 've forgot how many beers you 've drunk .
So let 's have another . House buys . [ Rumbling ]
I got to go . But wait .
What about the be - - See you . Me too . Wait up , Mike .
I 'll see you around . So long . Now , wait . Mike ! Ross !
Brand-new building , new construction .
Tell you .
[ Chuckles ]
Build garbage like this . I 'm gonna lose all of my customers .
The language is risqué , I admit it ,
but the overall message couldn 't have been more puritanical .
And , uh , why did you choose the topic of incest ?
When I was eight years old , I wanted to marry my father .
I guess all girls that age want to marry their fathers .
Anyway , I got over it pretty quickly .
He was a drunk .
One day , he just picked up and left my mother and me .
Did this leave any particular emotional feeling in you at the time ?
Emptiness .
That and pity for my mother .
I began to hate all men , and I - - [ Door Opens ]
Excuse me , Gerry . Oh , hi , Sandra .
How are you ? Hello , Emily .
Well , how come so early ?
I mean , I thought we 'd made it for 8 : 00 .
That 's the trouble . I can 't make it tonight . Huh ?
I have to see Bob . Oh , Bob .
You 're not upset , are you ? No , I 'm not upset .
I may be a little worried perhaps .
I mean , you have been seeing an awful lot of him , haven 't you , lately ?
Aw . [ Chuckles ]
Poor Bob . Hmm ?
He 's a sick and lonely kid .
I don 't see why people hate him so .
His mother was what you 'd call a woman of easy virtue .
No husband , no morals .
Here in Dunwich , anybody like that is also branded a witch .
[ Sighs ] Look , Sandra ,
I don 't believe those idiots ...
who tell me that our ancestors were Salem witch burners , all right ?
Okay , okay .
Gerry , I am sorry . Don 't worry .
I 'll see you tomorrow , around 9 : 00 ? Sure thing .
Bye . Bye .
So long , Sandra . Bye-bye . And take it easy .
[ Laughs ] Check . Bye .
Bye .
[ Door Closes ] [ Sighs ] Okay , Sandra , where were we ?
On the same old problem - - men .
Why do they have to make life so difficult ?
[ Screams ]
- [ Shrieks ] - Sandra !
Sandra .
Did he hurt you ? Did he claw you ?
Oh , he was just frightened .
Strange . It 's the first time he ever acted up like that .
[ Gerry ] He loves to have you pet him . He always comes to you when you 're here .
Something must have frightened him .
[ Horn Blaring ]
Honey , you give me the dirtiest thoughts .
I 'm telling ya , you 're gonna end up a dirty old man ,
a pervert , Peeping Tom .
Talk about box lunches . Man !
I saw a porno flick once ...
where this guy got so carried away , he humped himself to death .
Too much of a good thing . Yeah , but what a way to go .
Ah !
What 's the matter , you never see a body unearthed before ?
- Any law against looking ? - Yeah .
Okay . I 'm leaving .
Stupid . What time you got ?
Let 's flip to see who goes in the hole . All right .
Call it . Heads .
Tails . In the hole , sucker .
Shit .
♪ ♪ [ Whistling ]
♪ ♪ [ Whistling Continues ]
What are you still doing here , pal ? Ah , come on , fellas .
What do you want from us ? Nothing .
I 'm just curious about this girl here , that 's all .
Look , why don 't you guys go ahead with your work ,
and , uh , pretend I 'm not around .
Well , move , ' cause we 're almost finished .
[ Grunts ]
[ Whirring ]
[ Casket Hits Ground ]
[ Grunting ]
It 's 5 : 00 .
We 've bust our balls enough . Let 's go .
Amen .
Hey , hey . You 're not gonna - - You 're not gonna leave her like that , are you ?
Uh , union hours .
Anyways , what does she care ? She 's not in any hurry .
Is she ?
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Gasping Continues ]
[ Banging On Casket ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Faint Scream ]
[ Banging On Casket , Faint ]
[ Screams ] [ Airplane Passing Overhead ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Gasping Slows ]
[ Gasping Stops ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
- Oh , my God . - [ Screaming , Gasping ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Gasping Continues ]
[ Screams ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Whimpering Continues ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Theresa ] But for you , Mary would have suffered a terrible death .
I was just lucky .
No . It was written .
Are you acquainted with the Book of Enoch ?
A text which dates back to more than 4,000 years ago .
It contains man 's first recorded description ...
of his - - his boundless mortal fear in the face of malice itself ,
a demanding , implacable enemy whose search for blood is never satiated .
Mary , tell your experience - -
everything you witnessed during our last séance .
The city of the dead .
The living dead .
A cursed city ...
where the gates of hell have been opened .
[ Bell Clears Throat ]
Where , uh - - Where exactly is this city ?
I don 't know where it is .
All I know is that it 's called ... Dunwich .
Well , I 've never heard of it . Uh - -
How do you know ? I mean , how can you be so sure ?
I read the name ...
on a tombstone .
Mr. Bell , if those gates are left open , it may be the end of humanity .
We 've got to try to get them shut again .
At midnight on Monday , we go into All Saints ' Day .
The Night of the Dead begins then .
And if the portals of hell don 't get shut before ,
no dead body will ever be able to rest in peace again .
And so the dead will rise up and take over the Earth and - -
You must . You 've got to get to Dunwich .
You must reclose those gates .
[ Faint Squeaking ]
Bob ?
Bob , are you here ?
[ Gasps ]
Bob ?
Oh !
[ Bob Whimpering ] Bob ?
[ Whimpering , Sobbing ]
- Bob ! - [ Whimpering ]
Bob !
What 's happened ? Did you hurt yourself ?
[ Loud Yowling ]
Oh !
[ Yowling ]
- Bob ! - [ Yowling ]
Bob ! Bob !
Bob !
Bob , don 't leave me alone ! I 'm afraid .
[ Growling ] [ Whimpering ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Muffled Screaming ]
[ Rings ]
Hello .
Ah , it 's you , Mr. Robbins .
No , Emily 's not here , I 'm afraid .
- What 's that ? - She 's usually home this hour of the night .
I hope nothing 's happened to her . There 's been a lot of strange talk circulating .
Oh , come now , Mr. Robbins . Ignore it .
People here in this town thrive on that stuff . You should know that by now .
She 'll be home in another couple of minutes .
Ah , if you need me for any reason though , feel free to call .
I should be at the studio for at least another hour or so , okay ?
[ Laughs ] Good-bye , Mr. Robbins . Good-bye .
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
No , no . Come on , Tommy , please .
No . Please , Tommy . Hey .
What the devil 's the matter , honey ?
You treat me like I was a stranger . What have I done ? Tell me .
How come you picked out here to park ? This place gives me the willies .
Oh , Rose , go on . You 're not a little child now .
You don 't really believe in that stupid Salem witch stuff , do you ?
No , of course not .
[ Low Growling ]
[ Rose Moaning , Gasps ]
Now what 's wrong ? Sorry , Tommy , but ...
I keep thinking that , like , somebody 's out there spying on us .
Come on . There isn 't anyone out there .
Watch . I 'll turn on the headlights .
[ Gasping , Whimpering ]
[ Engine Rattling ]
[ Rattling ]
[ Rattling Continues ]
[ Screams ]
[ Gagging ]
[ Door Rattling ]
[ Retching ]
- [ Growling ] - [ Bone Crunching ]
[ Screaming ]
You know this Dunwich ? It 's not even on the map .
So , you don 't believe me , do you ?
That 's not the point . Just gonna be harder to find , that 's all .
We don 't even know where to start , do we ?
You know , I get my inner visions too , you know .
Just let me meditate over a bottle of scotch and , uh - -
And ?
I 'll take you anywhere .
[ Clanks ]
[ Police Radio Chatter ]
[ Man Sobbing ]
Well , she certainly wasn 't strangled .
Doesn 't seem to have been any kind of physical abuse .
What was the cause of her death then ? Some kind of cardiac arrest .
Only , that expression on her face looks like pure fear , like something scared her to death .
Scared her to - - Excuse me , Mr. Robbins .
Do you know if your daughter had a heart condition ?
No . No ?
No , no . She was - - [ Gerry ] Mr. Robbins .
Oh , God . God ! My little girl ! Well , what 's our procedure ?
Sit tight . Everything depends on the autopsy . I 'll sit tight .
You 'll get your orders after that from the D.A.
Okay , but let me hear from you , Joe .
What 's your opinion , Gerry ?
[ Sighs ] What 's there to say ? I 'm at a total loss .
It was - - It was Bob . That pervert . You can bet on it .
They should 've put him away for life after what he tried to do with poor little Ann Ross .
Listen , I 'll call out all cars after that boy .
And I wouldn 't be surprised if he could tell us what happened to Rosie Kelvin ...
and Frank 's kid too . [ Man ] Sheriff Russell !
Sheriff , what the dickens is this ?
[ Squishing ]
Good Lord .
That kid 's gonna fry . Mark my word .
[ Horns Blaring ]
So , your , uh , newspaper editor wouldn 't believe you , huh ?
Listen , when Adrian De Niro told me about two years ago ...
that I 'd meet a girl who 'd been buried alive , I didn 't believe him either .
I mean , I laughed right in his face .
De Niro was aware of many things .
He knew all about the city of the dead .
Okay . Okay . Say I believe you - -
Did you see - - When you were in this trance ,
did you see anything besides that tombstone ?
Oh , yes . I saw a priest ...
who , by hanging himself , opened the gates of hell .
He must be destroyed .
[ Woman ] ... our daily bread ,
and forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us .
And lead us not into temptation , but deliver us from evil .
For thine is the kingdom and the power and the glory .
Amen .
The Lord is my shepherd , I shall not want . This way , please .
He maketh me lie down in green pastures .
Yea though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death ... Where is she ?
Where is my Emily ? They 're still preparing her , Mrs. Robbins .
[ Sobbing ]
Mrs. Holden . Mrs. Holden ?
Yes . Mrs. Holden died last night .
And according to Dr. Thompson , was frightened to death .
Frightened to death ? That 's what he said - - fear .
Of what ?
Damned if I know , Doc . It 's the strangest thing I ever heard of .
Fear .
There 's been talk that Rose Kelvin and Tommy Fisher disappeared too .
They went to the movies last night , and nobody 's seen them since .
That makes five people who 've disappeared in the last 48 hours .
I think it 's Bob . I don 't believe in this superstitious nonsense .
Yeah . Maybe you 're right .
Sure . Remember two years ago when Bob took my little Ann into the woods ?
It was a miracle we found them in time .
Yeah , well , I say it 's him .
He 's the one causing all the trouble around here .
God only knows what he did to poor Emily .
All I know is the air in Dunwich is getting awful thick .
Soon as I can find somebody to buy my shop and my house , I 'm vamoosing .
You can bet your ass .
[ Mrs. Robbins Crying ] Calm down , dear . Take it easy . Calm down .
My baby . My poor baby .
You 'd - - You 'd - -
You 'd better take John-John out .
Yes , of course .
John-John , come on . Let 's go outside .
We 'll take a walk . You have to be strong now .
You have to find the courage to face life , John-John .
You have to be a man now . You know what I mean ? Hmm ?
[ Gasping ]
[ Door Squeaking ]
[ Rumbling ] [ Whimpers ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Whimpering ]
I 'm hungry . Good .
There 's a lollipop in the glove box .
Look , I 'm not joking . I 'm starved .
Look , you 're the one that got me out here in the armpit of the world ,
chasing your ... galloping cadavers .
Come on . Let 's go have a snack someplace , huh ?
Okay .
You , uh , wanna give up ?
Look , why don 't you get in the car and we 'll go and check out the local cuisine .
[ Sighs ] Don 't be upset .
Upset ? Who 's upset ?
According to your theory , we have less than 48 hours ...
before this , uh , All Saints ' Day .
Oh , please , not now . Do you mind ?
Come on . Let 's go check out the , uh , local cuisine , huh ?
[ Sighs ]
[ Growling ] [ Screaming ]
[ Squishing ] [ Screaming Continues ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Animal Cackling ]
[ Squeaking ]
[ Low Growling ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ John-John Whimpering ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Animal Cackles In Distance ]
[ Whimpering ]
Mommy !
Daddy ! Mommy ! Daddy !
Mommy ! Mommy ! What 's the matter , honey ?
Emily 's back . I saw her looking in the window .
She wanted to catch me . [ Sobbing ]
Emily went away forever , John-John . She 's in heaven .
I saw her , I swear . I saw her . I really did .
- We 'd better call the doctor . - I 'm all right . I don 't need a doctor .
I don 't want a doctor ! I saw her !
You 've had a big day . You 're upset .
We all are . Off you go now .
Go to bed . I don 't wanna go , Mommy . I 'm scared .
Emily 's gonna catch me . I know it .
Oh !
[ Clattering ]
[ Clattering Continues ]
[ Rings ]
[ Coughs , Sighs ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Hello ?
It 's me - - Sandra . You have to come right away .
No , there 's no time to explain . You wouldn 't believe me anyway .
Just come , please . I 'm having a nervous breakdown .
Yes , okay , Sandra . Just calm down and control yourself . What is it ?
[ Moaning ] There are only two possibilities .
Either I 'm going out of my mind , or something very , very strange is happening .
Look , take it easy . I 'll be there in 10 minutes , honey . Bye .
[ Handset Settles In Cradle ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Animal Cackling In Distance ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Groans ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Gerry , is that you ? Yeah , it 's me .
Come in .
What do you need that for ?
I don 't know . Maybe a crucifix would be better .
A crucifix ? What the hell are you talking about ?
[ Sighs ]
Tell me the truth .
Do you consider me a basket case ? No . Not at all . Why ?
You 're nurturing a pet neurosis . That 's all .
Like about 70 % of the female population of this country .
So , according to you , I 'm not stark raving mad ? At least not yet .
Don 't be silly . Of course not .
Sometimes you may drink a little more than you should ,
but that 's no reason to be taken away and put into a loony house .
No . No , I 'd rather not right now , and you really shouldn 't either .
All right . You better see for yourself . It 's in the kitchen .
The kitchen ? Uh-huh .
[ Exhales ]
[ Gasps ] Christ .
Was I just imagining things ?
No , it can 't be . It 's not - -
Uh-huh . It 's her - - Mrs. Holden .
This morning she was inside a coffin at the funeral home ,
and now she 's here in my kitchen .
How ? How did she get here ?
I don 't know . I heard a noise . I came to look , and there she was on my floor .
I called you right after . I thought I was losing my mind .
Okay . Let 's use our heads and not panic . Calm down .
We 've got to find out how she got here , all right ?
I couldn 't give a damn how she got here ! I just want her gone !
Look , let 's get out of here . I can 't take the sight of her .
Yeah . Yeah , yeah .
[ Sighs ] At this point , a good , stiff drink is the only medicine .
What are you gonna do ?
Well , I don 't believe in the Twilight Zone ,
so I guess I 'll call the sheriff on this matter .
And what will you tell him ? Well , exactly what you told me - -
That you heard this noise , that you came running and saw her there . And the rest is up to them .
[ Moaning ] [ Gasps ]
[ Moaning Continues ] [ Creaking ]
[ Gerry ] What was that ?
[ Low Growling ] [ Breathing Sharply ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Gerry ] It 's half closed . We left it wide open .
What the - -
Huh . Someone took her away . Or maybe she just left .
Don 't be ridiculous . Bodies don 't get up and walk away by themselves .
[ Roaring ] [ Gasps ]
[ Clattering ] She 's still here ! She 's still in the house !
[ Screams ] She 's in here ! Sandra .
I know she 's in the house . Sandra , get ahold of yourself .
I don 't want to see her anymore ! Sandra , this is no way to - -
Gerry , get her out ! Please ! For God 's sakes , calm down !
Tell her to go ! Yes . Yes .
She 's in here ! Do you hear her ? Gerry , she 's in here !
I can 't take it anymore ! Okay , Sandra . Sandra .
[ Clattering Stops ] Sandra , calm down .
Calm down . Come on . You hear ?
Calm down . Don 't let your imagination run away with you .
I don 't know what the hell is going on in here either , Sandra . [ Breathing Sharply ]
So we 're gonna take it step by step and search every room in the house , all right ?
And we 'll find the reason . All right , Sandra ? Now you 're gonna follow me .
Follow me now . Come on now .
That 's it .
All right ? All right .
Okay . I 'll do whatever you say .
[ Light Switch Clicks ]
[ Door Opens ] [ Light Switch Clicks ]
[ Sighs ]
I don 't think I 'll manage to sleep here tonight .
Well , if you want to stay at my studio or the house , you 're always welcome . [ Gasps ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Growling ] [ Sandra Screams ]
[ Breathing Sharply ]
[ Sandra ] Wh - - [ Exclaims ]
[ Gasping ] [ Gerry ] Oh , my God .
[ Sandra Moaning ]
Good God , it 's blood !
Blood ! Oh !
Oh !
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Priest ] Dunwich ? Yeah . Yes , yes , I know it .
[ Church Bells Ringing ] Odd that you 're looking for Dunwich .
Yeah , as a matter of fact , uh - - Yes , that 's the town where Father Thomas - -
Terrible . Oh , terrible !
You know that Dunwich was built on the ruins of the original Salem - -
the village of witches and heresy ... and evil .
Yes , but , uh , can you tell us how to get there ?
It 's not easy . You 'll have to go back ... towards the highway .
And as you approach it , there 's a road going left .
Mm-hmm . Blocked by a landslide .
That will take you to Dunwich . Thanks a lot .
Uh , just out of curiosity - -
[ Laughs ] Why are you folks going down there ?
[ Mary ] Uh - - Well , we 're just looking up a friend .
Oh . I see .
Thanks again .
[ Inhales , Sighs ]
The Lord help us .
[ Groans ]
[ Groans , Sighs ]
Hey . Bob .
Hi , Ann .
What are you doing in the backseat of my dad 's car ? I didn 't know where to sleep .
You won 't tell on me , will you ? No , of course not .
Only , you get some awful weird ideas . Come on . Smoke a little joint with me .
Only then you better split , okay ? [ Ross ] Ann !
- [ Both Gasp ] - It 's him ! Go on ! Get out of here !
What are you doing ? Nothing , Dad . We were just - -
Get in the house ! Get !
I-I - - I can explain everything , Mr. Ross !
Shut up , you bastard !
[ Whirring ] [ Screams ]
What were you trying to do to my daughter ? Huh ?
Please let me explain , Mr. Ross .
I was only looking for a place to sleep .
I swear !
Pervert ! Murderer ! No ! No .
No .
Oh !
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
No ! No !
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
[ Ringing ]
I guess there 's nobody in . That 's strange .
What do you plan on doing ? I have a feeling this is where the answer is .
We 've got to find the undertaker or someone from the funeral parlor . Maybe they 've gone to the cemetery .
You go . I 'll wait in your office .
I don 't think I could take a cemetery right now .
Fair enough .
[ Bell ] " Dweller of the twilight void . " That 's heavy . Well ?
Yes . That 's it .
That 's the very same tombstone that I saw in my trance .
Great .
Welcome to the city of the dead . Now what do we do ?
We must find the priest 's grave and uncover him .
There isn 't much time left . All Saints ' Day begins at midnight .
Well , where do we start ?
Okay . Well , it 's gotta be one of these .
You know , it 's a good thing he didn 't hang himself in Arlington .
[ Bell ] Hey ! Yes ?
Excuse me . Uh , I wonder if you could give us some information .
Sure .
Well , we 're , uh - - we 're looking for a tombstone of a - -
of a - - of a priest who hanged himself .
Father Thomas ?
We don 't know his name .
Well , why are you looking for his burial site ?
It 's a - -
It 's a long story - - one you might not want to believe .
Try me . I 'm just about ready to believe anything at this point .
And that 's the whole story .
My God in heaven . The living dead .
And that 's why you 're here in Dunwich ?
[ Gerry ] What do you want to do ? What are you hoping to accomplish ?
The death of Father Thomas ...
gave birth to some - - some evil -
[ Metal Creaking ] - [ Sandra Gasps ]
[ Wind Howling ]
- [ Sandra ] They 're worms ! Worms ! - [ All Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Howling Stops ] [ Panting ]
[ Worms Squishing ] [ All Groaning , Panting ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasping , Screaming ]
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Yeah ? Who 's speaking ?
All right , John-John . Now listen to me .
You take it easy , and you stay right there , and don 't move .
And I 'll be right over .
What happened ? [ Handset Settles In Cradle ]
That was Emily 's little brother , John-John .
He just told me that Emily killed her parents .
Emily died two days ago .
[ Faint Whimpering ]
[ Whimpering Continues ]
[ Wind Howling ]
Gerry ! Gerry !
I 'm scared , Gerry ! I 'm scared ! [ Gerry ] Easy now .
It 's all over . Everything 's going to be all right .
Would you girls take care of him , please ? [ Sandra ] Sure . Come on .
My car ? Yeah .
Okay .
In you get .
God . God almighty .
Totally butchered .
Literally ripped to shreds , those two .
You 're sure it was Emily ?
Yeah , but she was all different .
Emily was like - - She was like - - She was dead .
And she was eating Mommy and Daddy .
Poor kid . You poor darling .
Gerry . Gerry , listen .
We got to go to the funeral parlor .
And then we got to look for that - - that grave of the priest .
All right . Well ?
The kid all right ? Scared to death .
John-John , it 's all right . It 's gonna be all right . [ Engine Starts ]
It 's all over now .
Now listen , Sandra . Go to the studio with John-John ,
stay there , and don 't let him out of your sight . Yeah , sure .
Not for any reason . Listen , Gerry , we 'd better get a move on .
We only have a couple hours before All Saints ' Day . [ Door Closes ]
God knows what else could happen . [ Engine Starts ]
[ Animal Cackling ]
[ Animal Howls ]
[ Howling ]
[ Cackling ]
- [ Screaming ] - [ Growling ]
[ Bone Crunching ]
[ Screaming Continues ] [ Crunching Continues ]
[ Squishing ]
[ Bellowing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Gasps ] Emily !
No ! No . No !
- [ Bellowing Moan ] - Go away ! No !
Go away ! No !
Emily ! No ! [ Panting ]
Oh , John-John , thank God you 're safe , boy . [ Moaning Stops ]
Listen , there 's a police car around the corner . Mary 's there too .
You go straight to it . Go ! [ Gasps ]
[ Bellowing , Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Moaning Stops ] [ Wind Howling ]
Yeah , I 'm in car two with Sheriff Russell . It 's okay . It 's okay .
We 're on Main Street . [ Bell ] We got to go look for Father Thomas ' grave .
You want some of my men ? No , I think it 'd be better if you , uh , took care of the kid .
All right . I 'll take care of the kid . Stay here .
Yeah . Do what the sheriff tells you , okay ?
Mary ? Coming .
We 're doing a crisscross of the whole town , so you stay in touch , huh ?
[ Man On Radio ] You bet , buddy . Did he call ?
Yeah . Let 's get going .
[ Gate Creaks ]
[ Man ] We interrupt this program to bring you a special broadcast .
Dunwich police authorities have declared a state of emergency ...
effective immediately within Dunwich County .
All citizens are requested to return to their homes ...
as quickly as possible .
In case of necessity , contact this station - -
radio WDWC .
The telephone number is 825-9881 .
All citizens are urged to remain calm and to follow all instructions to the letter .
We repeat - - Mind telling me what 's going on ?
The dead are leaving their tombs .
- Ah , that 's a load of crap . - Crap or not , I 'm taking my money .
I 'm closing my doors till tomorrow morning ,
and I 'm not opening for anybody . [ Door Clatters ]
[ Moaning ] [ Scraping ]
[ Man On Radio ] ... effective immediately within Dunwich County .
All citizens are requested to return to their homes ... [ Scraping Continues ]
as quickly as possible . [ Moaning Continues ]
[ Creaking , Scraping ] [ Man On Radio Continues ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Loud Rustling ]
[ Rustling Continues ] [ Creatures Howling ]
[ Creature Shrieks ] [ Animal Cackling ]
[ Rustling Continues ] [ Animal Sounds Continue ]
[ Animal Cackling ] [ Sighs ]
[ Loud Rustling ]
I believe Father Thomas is buried in his family tomb over there .
[ Cackling Continues ]
[ Rustling ]
Guess what .
It 's All Saints ' Day .
[ Rustling Continues ] [ Animals Howling , Cackling ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Bellowing Moan ]
[ Gasping Continues ]
[ Screaming ]
Oh , no !
[ Gasping ] [ Moaning ]
[ Gasping Continues ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Screams ]
Well - -
[ Sighs ] The Thomas family tomb . Now what ?
I wish I had a cigar . Shall we open it ?
Lady had a vision .
You 're sure ? Mary ?
Ready ? Oh , boy . Here we go .
[ All Grunting ] [ Scraping ]
That 's it .
[ Animal Cackling ]
Be careful .
Here you go .
Thanks .
[ Distant Dripping ]
Oh ! Oh .
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
- [ Screaming ] - [ Rat Squeaking ]
Oh ! [ Gasping ]
[ Squeaking Continues ]
Hold on to this and let me try to give Bell a hand .
[ Mary ] For God 's sake , hurry . It 's past midnight .
[ Grunting ]
My God . Someone must have broken in from the other side .
Or broken out . [ Exhales ]
Well , now what do we do ?
I want to go take a look . Give me a hand . [ Crowbar Clatters On Ground ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Man ] Having received no further bulletins on police emergency operations ,
which are still in progress ,
we can only confirm our previous special broadcast .
Citizens are requested to remain in their homes . [ Moaning ]
Under no circumstances should anyone try to reach the state turnpike .
We repeat - - Do not panic . Remain in your homes .
Stay tuned to WDWC for further bulletins .
For those who have just tuned in , we repeat our previous bulletin .
Dunwich police authorities have declared a state of emergency ...
effective immediately in Dunwich County .
All citizens - -
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Gasps , Screams ] [ Squeaking ]
[ Gasps ] No !
[ Screaming ]
[ Sobbing ]
Sandra .
[ Screaming ] [ Bone Crunching ]
- [ Rats Squeaking ] - [ Screams ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Panting ] No .
No .
[ Mary Panting ]
[ Bellowing Roar ]
[ Gurgling ]
[ Mary Sobbing ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Low Growling ]
[ Howling ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Gasping Continues ]
[ Bellowing ]
[ Corpses Moaning ]
[ Wailing ]
[ Wailing Continues ]
[ Gasping , Wailing ]
[ Wailing ]
[ Screams ]
[ Wailing Continues ]
[ Wails ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps ] Mary !
Gerry ! Gerry ! [ Laughing ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Wind Howling ] [ Gasps ]
[ Mary ] No . No !
[ Moaning ] No !
[ Screams ] [ Thunderclap ]